Guide to the Ireland House Oral History Collection AIA.030
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- C
  - Cassidy, Daniel, Jun 20, 2008; cuid34498 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Daniel Cassidy (b. Brooklyn, New York, 1943, d. San Francisco, California, 2008) was a musician, author, labor activist, and teacher. He was the founder and co-director of the Irish Studies Program at the New College of California in San Francisco, CA. His book How the Irish Invented Slang: The Secret Language of the Crossroads won the American Book Award in 2007.
    In this oral history Cassidy, author and scholar, traces the link between his family history his involvement in Irish Studies, and the origins of his research which culminated in How the Irish Invented Slang. In a largely chronological manner, Cassidy starts by discussing his Brooklyn roots; his parents; his education; Vietnam; his battle with drugs and twenty-three month stay at Phoenix House; friendships with comedian George Carlin and musician Kenny Rankin; and the meaning of Irish identity. After starting off with a clear New York/East Coast focus, the narrative then shifts geographically to Cassidy's life in California and most particularly in San Francisco. Topics like his writing (his screenplay, The Volunteer, was sold to Francis Ford Coppola), labor organizing, and his move into teaching are covered. Cassidy engages in a detailed discussion of language and slang, in the context of Irish American culture, with his long-time friend Peter Quinn, author of Banished Children of Eve. Cassidy provides an insider's perspective on the day JFK was assassinated as a rookie journalist in the newsroom of the New York Times. The interview concludes with Cassidy emphasizing the extent to which Irish American scholarship awaits thorough excavation, by contending that immense research potential sits like 'gold nuggets' on the ground.
    Danny Cassidy was interviewed in his home in San Francisco on July 20, 2008 by Peter Quinn. This oral history was digitally recorded on a Marantz PMD660. It is 148 minutes and 49 seconds long, on three CDs, and has been logged at five minute intervals.
    This interview has been logged at five-minute intervals, and the Word file is available upon request at tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu.
  - Clancy, Cummin, Apr 29, 2009; cuid34499 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Cummin Clancy (b. Oughterard, County Galway, Ireland, 1922) is an insurance broker with the firm of Clancy and Clancy Brokerage Ltd. in Garden City, New York. A former Olympic athlete (1948 Games in London), he is the founder of the Long Island Chapter of the Friendly Sons of St. Patrick.
    This oral history was digitally recorded on a Marantz PMD660. The interview is approximately 80 minutes long, on 2 CDs. The interview took place on April 29, 2009, and the interviewer was Myriam Nyhan.
  - Clancy, Liam, Mar 29, 2009; cuid34500 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Liam Clancy (b. Carrick-On-Suir, County Tipperary, Ireland, 1935, d. Cork, County Cork, Ireland, 2009), musician, vocalist, and youngest member of the Clancy Brothers and Tommy Makem, a folk supergroup which revolutionized Irish traditional music in the United States. He published his memoir The Mountain of the Women in 2001.
    This oral history was digitally recorded on a Marantz PMD660. The interview is approximately 90 minutes long, on 2 CDs. The interview took place on March 29, 2009, at the Washington Square Hotel, and the interviewer was Myriam Nyhan.
  - Clinton Stables, 2014; cuid34769 (Box Electronic records, E-records TW_AIA_30_ER_2)
    Historical Note
    Clinton Stables was created in 2003 when 15 carriage drivers bought and renovated a 19th century stable on 52nd Street in Manhattan, New York.
    This interview was conducted by Linda Dowling Almeida at Clinton Stables on March 25th 2014. The interview includes Conor McHugh, the manager of Clinton Stables and a former carriage driver; Christina Hanson, a carriage driver in 2014; and Eddie Hayes, the stable's farrier. McHugh describes his early memories of farm horses in Ireland, his immigration to the United States (US) in 1986, and his opinions on the legislation needed to protect the carriage trade. McHugh recounts the founding of Clinton Stables in 2003 and the history of the stable building. Hanson explains the history of carriage rides in New York City and the carriage driver licensing held by the New York City Department of Health. Hayes recounts his father's farrier business in Jersey City, New Jersey and New York City and his personal tips on horse management and horse husbandry.
  - Cody, Rena, Jul 26, 2013; cuid34501 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    Rena Cody (b. Templemore, Co. Tipperary, Ireland, 1952), co-founder of the Irish Immigration Center in Boston, she worked at Neponset Health Center. She returned to Ireland in 1993 and works as a local government Social Exclusion Officer.
  - Cole, Williams Rossa, 2015; cuid34770 (Box Electronic records, E-records TW_AIA_30_ER_95)
    Williams Rossa Cole was born in 1968 in New York, New York. He is a filmmaker.
    This interview was conducted by Miriam Nyhan at New York University's Glucksman Ireland House in New York, New York on June 3, 2015. The interview covers Williams Rossa Cole's family and the life of his great-grandfather Jeremiah O'Donovan Rossa. Cole discusses his family, including his father, WIlliam Rossa Cole, and their ancestor O'Donovan Rossa. He recounts stories told in his family about O'Donovan Rossa and his own relationship to this history. He discusses Rebel Rossa, a documentary about O'Donovan Rossa, which Cole was filming at the time of the interview. He describes the impetus for Rebel Rossa, citing his learning more about O'Donovan Rossa's dynamite campaign and his work for Irish freedom, and the approaching centenary of O'Donovan Rossa's death in 2015.
  - Collins, John, Apr 5, 2011; cuid34502 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    John P. Collins (b. Manhattan, New York, 1939), the son of immigrants from Co. Limerick, has been a judge for the New York City Criminal Court since 1978. He received his B.S. from Fordham University and his J.D. from New York University. In the 1960s he was active in the movement to counter restrictions on emigration from Ireland.
  - Conlon, Ray, Aug 24, 2010; cuid34503 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Connolly, Marie, Jun 23, 2009; cuid34504 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Marie Connolly (b. New York, 1935), raised in County Longford, Ireland, from the age of two, she returned to Astoria, NY as a teenager in 1949. She later worked in admissions for the Berkeley School and the Wood School in Manhattan before raising three children on Long Island.
    This oral history was digitally recorded on a Marantz PMD660. The interview is approximately 100 minutes long, on 2 CDs. The interview took place in Wantagh, NY, on February 26, 2009, and the interviewer was Myriam Nyhan.
  - Conway, Kevin, May 25, 2013; cuid34505 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    Kevin Conway (b. Manchester, England, 1966) grew up near Manchester, UK, where his parents had emigrated in the 1950s. The family returned to Finny, Co. Galway in 1981. He came to the United States in 1988, and again in 1990, married an American wife in 1991, and heads the imaging Research Laboratory at Massachussetts General Hospital.
  - Cook, Terri Connolly, Oct 30, 2009; cuid34506 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Subject headings have been created by track number, and the Excel file is available upon request at tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu.
    The interview with Terri Connolly Cook touches on several themes, including: being an Irish Catholic woman in corporate America; 9/11 and Irish terrorism; claddagh rings found after 9/11; Irish America and being Democrat-('we were all raised to be democrats') and the move to Republican party; Obama and the younger generation; and JFK.
    This oral history was digitally recorded on a Marantz PCM660. The interview is approximately 110 minutes long. The interview took place in New York on October 20, 2008, and the interviewer was Myriam Nyhan.
    Terri Connolly Cook (b. New York, New York, 1942), retired fashion industry executive, grew up in the Mott Haven and Bedford Park sections of the Bronx, New York. The daughter of 1920s immigrants, she curated the 2008 photo exhibition "The Monaghan Society in New York" at the Monaghan County Museum in Ireland.
  - Cooke, Caitriona, May 25, 2013; cuid34507 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    Caitriona Cooke (b. Dublin, Ireland, 1951) was a schoolteacher in Ireland who re-trained as a conservation consultant in Boston, specializing in energy efficiency systems for buildings.
  - Corcoran, Sr. Eileen, Jul 14, 2011; cuid34508 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Eileen Corcoran of the Sisters of St. Dominic (b. Bronx, New York, 1941), the daughter of Irish immigrants from Counties Donegal and Cork, was raised in the Parkchester section of the Bronx. Through her vocation with the Dominican sisters, she has worked on creating art retreats, fundraising, and teaching religious and physical education, most recently at Our Lady Queen of Martyrs in Centerport, New York.
  - Corrigan, Louise, 2015; cuid34771 (Box Electronic records, E-records TW_AIA_30_ER_80)
    Louise Corrigan was born in 1982 in Dublin, Ireland and was raised in Kilmeade, County Kildare. She received her Bachelor's degree from University College Dublin in 2005 and received her legal training at the Law Society of Ireland in Dublin. She was admitted to the New York State Bar in 2007 and worked for the New York County Defender's Office between 2008 and 2014. She returned to Ireland in 2014 and established a legal practice offering immigration advice to Irish and American citizens. In 2015, Corrigan co-founded the the Dublin chapter of Irish Network USA.
    This interview was conducted by Íde B. O'Carroll at Louise Corrigan's home in Dublin, Ireland on August 5, 2015. The interview covers Corrigan's education and working life. Corrigan discusses her education at University College Dublin and her legal training at the Law Society of Ireland in Dublin. She discusses her decision to study for the New York State Bar exam and her work in the New York County Defender's Office between 2008 and 2014. She describes her connections in New York with other Irish immigrants, particularly her association with Irish Network USA and a community of Irish dancers. She explains the support she received from these communities during her time in the United States. She recounts meeting her husband in New York in 2012 and deciding to return to Ireland in 2014. She describes her legal practice advising Irish and American citizens on immigration issues and her work co-founding the Dublin chapter of Irish Network USA.
  - Costello, Anne O'Connor, 2014; cuid34772 (Box Electronic records, E-records TW_AIA_30_ER_67)
    Anne O'Connor Costello was born in 1958 in Tubber, County Clare, Ireland. She graduated from nursing school in 1979. She immigrated to the United States in 1985 and settled in Boston, Massachusetts. She moved to Northern Ireland in 1999 with her husband and their four sons.
    This interview was conducted by Miriam Nyhan at New York University's Glucksman Ireland House in Manhattan, New York on October 23, 2014. The interview covers Anne O'Connor Costello's early life in Ireland and her life in the United States (US). Costello describes her family members, her childhood, and her education. She discusses the importance of Irish sports to her, in particular hurling and camogie, and describes the schools she attended nursing school. She describes her experiences in nursing school and working as a nurse in Galway after graduation in 1979. She discusses her first visits to Boston, Massachusetts in the early 1980s; her first impressions of the city; and her decision to immigrate to the US in 1985. She also discusses the importance of traveling frequently between Ireland and the US to her decision to settle in the US. She discusses her and her husband's decision to move to Northern Ireland in the 1999, citing her sons's interest in Irish sports and the difference in values between Ireland and the US. She recounts their decision to settle in Belfast, the differences in the city between 1999 and the time of the interview, and her happiness with her life in Belfast. Throughout the interview, Costello discusses the importance of camogie in her life, in both Ireland and the US.
  - Costello, Frank, Apr 9, 2009; cuid34509 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Frank Costello (b. Newark, New Jersey, 1955) is Director of Costello Associates in Belfast, a firm that promotes community development investment in Ireland and the U.S. Born in Newark, NJ, he attended boarding school at St. Mary's College, Galway, while a teenager, later earning a Ph.D. from Boston College in 1992. He is the author of The Irish Revolution and its Aftermath 1916–1923: Years of Revolt (2002).
    This oral history was digitally recorded on a Marantz PMD660. The interview is approximately 3 hours long, on 2 CDs. The interview took place in Newark, NJ, on April 9, 2009, and the interviewer was Myriam Nyhan.
  - Cronacher, Lola Lee, Feb 15, 2011; cuid34510 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    Lola Lee Cronacher (b. Floral Park, New York, 1934) is a retired school teacher. Raised in Hollis, Queens, her mother was from Tralee, Co. Kerry and her father was an Irish American from Brooklyn.
  - Crotty, Paul, Mar 10, 2009; cuid34511 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    Some of the topics this interview covers include: Buffalo Irish; Crotty's grandparents, who were immigrants from Clare, his dad, a lawyer, and he is a judge; Irishness, Catholicism, Democrats; worldview of Irish Catholics when he was coming up; how all Irish Catholic communities had a similar make-up (which he noticed when he went to Notre Dame); and Ireland and poverty.
    This oral history was digitally recorded on a Marantz PMD660. The interview is approximately 120 minutes long, on 2 CDs. The interview took place in New York City on March 10, 2009, and the interviewer was Myriam Nyhan.
    Paul Crotty (b. Buffalo, New York, 1941), US District Court Justice for the Southern District of New York, was raised in Buffalo, New York. He is the grandson of immigrants from Co. Clare and a former partner in the law firm of Donovan, Leisure, Newton & Irvine.
  - Crotty, Vincent, 2016; cuid34773 (Box Electronic records, E-records TW_AIA_30_ER_68)
    Vincent Crotty was born in 1964 in Cork City, County Cork, Ireland. He grew up in Kanturk, County Cork. He immigrated to the United States in 1990 as an undocumented immigrant and attended the Cambridge School of Adult Education in Cambridge, Massachusetts. He married in 2003.
    This interview was conducted by Íde B. O'Carroll on October 28, 2016 in Dorchester, Massachusetts. The interview contains Vincent Crotty's family history and his early interest in art. He describes how he traveled to the United States and started selling his artwork in Aisling Gallery in Hingham, Massachusetts in 1990. He recounts his mentor John Kilroy's advice to relearn his rendering skills at the Cambridge School of Adult Education in Cambridge,. Crotty recounts how Father Dan Finn and Father Tim Sullivan of St. Mark's Parish in Dorchester helped him with employment, housing, and his status as an undocumented immigrant.
  - Culhane, Noreen M., Dec 7, 2006; cuid34512 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    The interview is approximately 1 hour, 4 minutes, and 40 seconds long. The interview took place on December 7, 2006, and the interviewers were Lorraine Saxton and Marion R. Casey.
    Noreen M. Culhane (b. Bronx, New York, 1950) is an Executive Vice President at the New York Stock Exchange and the 1970 New York Rose of Tralee.
  - Cullen, Fr. Daniel, May 6, 2009; cuid34513 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Father Daniel Cullen (b. Larne, County Antrim, Ireland, 1920) served in the Society of African Missions (SMA) for more than sixty years. He worked in Liberia and then, for nineteen years, as a fundraiser for the SMA in the United States.
    This oral history was digitally recorded on a Marantz PMD660. The interview is on 2 CDs. The interview took place in Tenafly, NJ, on May 6, 2009, and the interviewer was Myriam Nyhan.
  - Cullen, James, Dec 9, 2011; cuid34514 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    James Cullen (b. Astoria, New York, 1945) was born in New York but stayed with relatives in Co. Offaly for some time as a child. The son of Irish immigrants from Cos. Offaly and Roscommon, he has had a long career in law and was elected as the first President of the Brehon Law Society n 1978. He is a retired brigadier general in the United States Army Reserve Judge Advocate General's Corps, and was involved in the movement to ban the use of torture by the United States after the Abu Ghraib abuses were brought to light.
  - Cullen, Kevin, Oct 18, 2013; cuid34515 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    Kevin Cullen (b. Malden, MA, 1958) is a Pulitzer Prize- winning Boston Globe journalist who has reported on immigration, Northern Ireland, and the Whitey Bulger case. He also contributes to Irish radio NewsTalkFM.
  - Cullimore, John, Jul 27, 2013; cuid34516 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    John Cullimore (b. Wexford Town, Co. Wexford, Ireland, 1959) established a successful painting/renovation company specializing in the rehabilitation of Victorian homes in Cambridge, MA; returned to Ireland in 1996.
  - Cullinane, John, 2015; cuid34774 (Box Electronic records, E-records TW_AIA_30_ER_56)
    John Cullinane was born in 1934 in Dedham, Massachusetts. He graduated in 1952 from Arlington High School in Arlington and attended Northeastern University in Boston. In 1968 he founded the software company Cullinet.
    This interview was conducted by Íde B. O'Carroll on April 27, 2015 in Dedham, Massachusetts. The interview covers John Cullinane's family history and early career. He recounts his founding of the database management software company Cullinet and its early success in the software industry. He describes orchestrating the merger of the Ireland Fund and the American Ireland Foundation in 1983. Cullinane recounts connecting Irish programmers to American investors by hosting C.E.O. seminars in Boston in 1993. He describes his involvement with Barack Obama's political campaign in 2008 as the head of outreach for Irish Americans.
  - Cummings, Michael, 2014; cuid34775 (Box Electronic records, E-records TW_AIA_30_ER_23)
    Michael Cummings was born in Springfield, Massachusetts in 1946. He attended St. Anselm's College in New Hampshire from 1964 to 1967 and received his master's degree in public administration from New York University.
    This interview was conducted by Danielle Zach in New York, New York on September 8, 2014. The interview covers Michael Cummings's family's history of immigration to the United States and his early childhood. He recounts the beginning of his Irish republican activism in the 1970s, describing the events of Bloody Sunday in 1972 as his inspiration. He describes his involvement with having the MacBride Principles be accepted as US foreign policy in 1984 and his associations with Irish Northern Aid Committee (NORAID), the Irish American Unity Conference, and the Ancient Order of the Hibernians.
  - Cunningham, Annette, 2016; cuid34776 (Box Electronic records, E-records TW_AIA_30_ER_69)
    Annette Cunningham was born in Manhattan, Illinois. She was a member of the Irish Government's Export Board, Córas Tráchtála, as the communications director for North America.
    This interview was conducted by Neeve Kelly at New York University's Glucksman Ireland House in Manhattan, New York on July 25, 2016. The interview contains Annette Cunningham's mother's immigration story and Cunningham's marketing career. She describes her duties as the communications director for North America for the Irish Government's Export Board, Córas Tráchtála. She recalls how her marketing skills helped to create an identity for Ireland as a source for high quality luxury products.
  - Cunningham, Joseph, Mar 28, 2011; cuid34517 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    Joseph Cunningham (b. Crusheen, Co. Clare, Ireland, 1912) emigrated to New York in 1929 and played accordion for sixty years with the Joe Cunningham Band. He raised five children in Yonkers.
  - Curran, Sean, Mar 28, 2009; cuid34518 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    This oral history was digitally recorded on a Marantz PMD660. The interview is approximately 150 minutes long, on 3 CDs. The interview took place in New York on March 18, 2009, and the interviewer was Myriam Nyhan.
    Sean Curran (b. Boston, Massachusetts, 1961) a modern dancer and choreographer, is the son of immigrants from Counties Cork and Roscommon. A former Irish step dancer, lead dancer with the Bill T. Jones/Arnie Zane Dance Company, and cast member of Stomp!, he founded the Sean Curran Company in New York in 1997.
- D
  - Daly, Anita, Jun 28, 2011; cuid34519 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    Anita Daly (b. Brooklyn, New York, 1953) is the founder and president of Daly Communications, a music marketing company that includes a roster of Irish musicians such as Van Morrison, Clannad, and Eileen Ivers.
  - D'Arcy, Kathleen Walsh (two interviews), Feb 12, 2009-Apr 22, 2009; cuid34520 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    Kathleen Kearney Walsh Papers (AIA 029)
    Kathleen Walsh D'Arcy (b. 1948), a social worker, writer, and organizer of the St. Pat's for All Parade in Queens (est. 2005), is the daughter of 1920s immigrants from Co. Offaly and Co. Tipperary. She co-edited two fiction collections by Irish women writers, Territories of the Voice (1990) and A Green and Mortal Sound (2001).
    Some of the themes that D'Arcy focuses on in these interviews include: class divisions in Irish post-war community and how Kathleen related in an up-scale school environment; growing up in an extremely Irish-oriented household; parents were very open and Kathleen thinks that they were unique in that way (track 4); she was in a convent, as a novitiate, for a year; McNiff school of dancing (track 5); and her work in Dublin in the early 1970s.
    This oral history was digitally recorded on a Marantz PMD660. The interview took place over two sessions: February 12, 2009 and April 22, 2009. The 2/12/09 interview is approximately 2 hours long and on two CDs, and the 4/22/09 interview is approximately 70 minutes long. The interviews both took place in New York, and the interviewer was Myriam Nyhan.
  - Davis, Ashley, Apr 8, 2011; cuid34521 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    Ashley Davis (b. Kansas City, Kansas, 1976) is a singer of both her own original music and of traditional songs in the Celtic languages. She received her MA from the University of Limerick in Traditional Irish Music. In 2006 she traveled to the Isle of Man to capture and record the native Manx language as well as the stories and music of the island. She released a CD Songs of the Celtic Winter in 2012.
  - Deegan, Seamus, Feb 25, 2011; cuid34522 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    Seamus Deegan (b. Dunlavin, Co. Wicklow, 1942), a social worker, emigrated in 1966, to serve as a priest for the Diocese of Rockville Centre in Mineola, New York. In 1974 he decided to leave the priesthood and pursued graduate studies in psychology and social work.
  - Deenihan, Jimmy, 2016; cuid34777 (Box Electronic records, E-records TW_AIA_30_ER_78)
    Jimmy Deenihan was born in 1952 in Finuge, County Kerry, Ireland. He graduated from Thomond College of Education in County Limerick. He worked as a secondary teacher and played Gaelic football until 1982. He was appointed Senator in the Seanad Éireann in 1983 and served until 1987. Between 1987 and 2016 he served as a Teachta Dála in the Dáil Éireann. He held multiple ministerial posts during his time in politics, including Minister for Culture, Heritage and the Gaeltacht and Minister of State for the Diaspora.